Register of the Monique Garnier-Lançon Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1968-1991 (Box 36-44)
  - South Africa - Politics and government (1978-1989), 1982-1984
    - 1982-1983 (Folder 42: 6)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 43: 1-3)
    - 1984 (Folder 43: 4-5)
  - Soviet Union,., 1986-1989 (Folder 43: 6)
  - Strategic Defense Initiative ("Star Wars"), 1982-1986 (Box 44)
    - 1982-1983 (Folder 44: 1)
    - 1984-1986 (Folder 44: 2)
  - Surinam, 1985-1986 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Turkey, undated (Folder 44: 4)
  - Union européenne féminine, 1987 (Folder 44: 5)
  - West European Defence Association, 1985 (Folder 44: 6)
  - Women and Families for Defence, 1983 (Folder 44: 7)
- Printed Matter, 1965-1995 (Box 45-50)
  Brochures, monographs, newsletters, and serial issues, largely relating to issues of defense policy and international terrorism, arranged alphabetically by physical form and chronologically therein
  - Brochures and pamphlets, 1982-1988
    - 1982-1984 (Folder 45: 1)
    - 1985-1988 (Folder 45: 2)
  - Monographs, 1981-1995
    - 1981 (Folder 45: 3)
    - 1982 (Folder 45: 4)
    - 1983 (Folder 45: 5-6)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 46: 1-2)
    - 1985 (Folder 46: 3-4)
    - 1988 (Folder 46: 5)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - 1994 (Folder 47: 2)
    - 1995 (Folder 47: 3)
  - Serial issues
    - General, 1965-1992
      - 1965 (Folder 47: 4)
      - 1979-1982 (Folder 47: 5)
      - 1983 (Folder 47: 6-7)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 48: 1-3)
      - 1986 (Folder 48: 4-6)
      - 1987-1992 (Folder 48: 7)
    - Newsletters (Box 49)
      - ABC-Berichte, nos. 71 and 74, 1985 (Folder 49: 1)
      - The Aida Parker Newsletter, nos. 10, 14, 18-25, 30-41, 1983-1984 (Folder 49: 2)
      - Analysis (formerly Notes and Analysis), 1985 May - 1986 October (Folder 49: 3)
      - Backgrounder, nos. 277, 281, 294, 314, 1983 (Folder 49: 4)
      - Early Warning
        - 1984 June-July (Folder 49: 5)
        - 1986 January-December (Folder 49: 6)
        - 1987 January-November (Folder 49: 7)
      - Exchange
        - 1985
          - January-June (Folder 49: 8)
          - July-December (Folder 49: 9)
        - 1986 (Box 50)
          - January-June (Folder 50: 1)
          - July-December (Folder 50: 2)
        - 1987 January-December (Folder 50: 3)
        - 1988 June-August (Folder 50: 4)
      - High Frontier Newsletter, vol. IV, nos. 3-4, 1986 (Folder 50: 5)
      - Soviet Presswatch, vol. 1, no. 2, 1985 November 15 (Folder 50: 6)
      - World Briefing, 1989 January - 1990 January (Folder 50: 7)
- Photographs, 1982-1983 (Box 51)
  Prints arranged chronologically
  - Twenty-four prints depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon at various conferences and receptions, undated (Folder 51: 1)
  - One print depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon with the Mayor of Jerusalem, Teddy Kollek, undated (Folder 51: 2)
  - Seven prints depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon during an official visit to Washington, D.C., c., 1982 (Folder 51: 3)
    Includes four prints depicting Garnier-Lançon with the Mayor of Washington, Marion Barry
  - Seven prints depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon on a visit to South Africa, 1982 November (Folder 51: 4)
  - One print depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon with Senator John Tower, Washington, D.C., 1983 September 12 (Folder 51: 5)
  - Six prints depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon visiting the National Museum of American Art, Washington, D.C., c. 1985 (Folder 51: 6)
  - Three prints depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon at a conference in Washington, D.C., c. 1985 (Folder 51: 7)
    Includes one print depicting Garnier-Lançon with Jeane R. Kirkpatrick
  - One print depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon with Nancy and Ronald Reagan at the White House, Washington, D.C., 1985 February 8 (Folder 51: 8)
  - One print depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon with Raymond Barre, Paris, 1986 January (Folder 51: 9)
  - One print depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon with Caspar Weinberger, Washington, D.C., 1987 May 1 (Folder 51: 10)
  - Three identical prints depicting Charles de Gaulle, undated (Folder 51: 11)
  - Three identical prints depicting Charles de Gaulle, undated (Folder 51: 12)
  - Two prints depicting a conference in Prague, undated (Folder 51: 13)
    Includes one print depicting Vaclav Havel
- Sound Recordings, 1981-1987 (Box 51-52)
  Compact sound cassettes, sound disc, and sound tape reel, arranged alphabetically by physical form and chronologically therein
  - Compact sound cassettes, 1981-1987
    - Couve de Murville, Maurice, undated (Folder 51: 14)
    - Debré, Michel, undated (Folder 51: 15-16)
    - Dominati, Jacques, undated (Folder 51: 17)
    - Druon, Maurice, undated (Folder 51: 18)
    - "Elections municipales - portraits,", undated (Folder 51: 19)
    - Gaulle, Charles de, undated (Folder 51: 20)
    - Guichard, Olivier with Yvon Bourges and Maurice Papon, undated (Folder 51: 21)
    - Jacquet, Marc and Achille Peretti, undated (Folder 51: 22)
    - John Paul II, undated (Folder 51: 23)
    - Nye, Joseph and Michael Dukakis, undated (Folder 51: 24)
    - Peyrefitte, Alain, undated (Folder 51: 25)
    - Rabourdin, (?) and René Tomasini, undated (Folder 51: 26)
    - Chirac, Jacques, 1981 February 17 (Folder 51: 27)
    - Debré, Michel, 1981 February 24 (Folder 51: 28)
    - Garnier-Lançon, Monique, Lebanon radio, 1982 December 22 (Folder 51: 29)
    - European Institute for Security Matters (EIS) conference, 1986 June 16-17 (Folder 51: 30-32)
    - "Ouverture sur la vie," with Monique Garnier-Lançon, 1987 January 22 (Folder 51: 33-34)
  - Sound disc (45 rpm), 1983 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    "Si j'avais une faucille," Internationale de la Résistance
  - Sound tape reel (1/4-inch), undated (Folder 52: 2)
    "A bâtons rompus," with Anne Slack and Monique Garnier-Lançon
- Videorecordings, 1980-1986 (Box 52)
  Videocassettes arranged chronologically
  - French television program on Fidel Castro, undated (Folder 52: 3)
    VHS videocassette (PAL)
  - "Soviet flag,", undated (Folder 52: 4)
  - Video report from the Great Cities of the World Conference, Boston, Massachusetts, 1980 September 21-27 (Folder 52: 5)
    VHS videocassette
  - "La guerre en face," French television program produced by Yves Montand,., 1985 (Folder 52: 6)
  - "Year of the Struggle," documentary on political violence in South Africa, 1986 (Folder 52: 7)
- Oversize Materials and Memorabilia, 1980-1983 (Box 53)
  Print, posters, and political buttons
  - One large print depicting Monique Garnier-Lançon and others at a European Institute for Security Matters (EIS) conference, Paris, 1980 June (Folder 53: 1)
  - Five posters produced by the Coalition for Peace through Security, United Kingdom, c. 1983 (Folder 53: 2-6)
  - Six political buttons, with three relating to Vaclav Havel, undated (Folder 53: 7)